# MUHAMMAD DAANIYALL ABD RAHMAN

Department of Economics, Faculty of Economics and Management, Universiti Putra Malaysia, 43400 Serdang, Selangor Tel: +603-8946 7621 | Fax: +603-8948 6188 | Email: daaniyall@upm.edu.my | Email: daaniyall@gmail.com

Institute of Agriculture and Food Policy Studies, Universiti Putra Malaysia, Putra-Infoport, Jalan Kajang-Puchong, 43400 Serdang, Selangor Tel: +603-8947 1097 | Fax: +603-8943 2611 | Email: daaniyall@upm.edu.my | Email: daaniyall@gmail.com



## Employment

 Tutor at Universiti Putra Malaysia (UPM)

## Areas of expertise

- Development Economics
- Input-Output Analysis
- Sustainability Analysis

## Research interests

Primary interest is on the application of economy-wide models for policy analysis. Among the recent works include:

- Income distribution and poverty
- Labor market and demographic
- Trade and multi-country analysis
- Global value chain
- Large-scale input-output database development and comparison
- Multi regional input-output table comparison

### **PROFILE**

Muhammad Daaniyall Abd Rahman (Daani) was born in Pekan, Pahang on May 19, 1986. Daani obtained his PhD from the University of Sydney, Australia in 2018. Daani started his career as a Tutor, at the Department of Economics, Universiti Putra Malaysia (UPM) in 2010. Input-output analysis, and development economics are his areas of expertise.

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D (Input-Output Economics), Center for Integrated Sustainability Analysis, University of Sydney, Australia

Master of Science (Economics), Universiti Putra Malaysia Bachelor of Economics (Hons), Universiti Putra Malaysia

#### PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP

International Input-Output Association, IIOA (2015—present)

## **WORKING EXPERIENCES**

Tutor, Department of Economics, UPM (2010-current)
Research Associate, Institute of Agricultural and Food Policy Studies, UPM (2017-current)
Visiting Scholar, University of Groningen, the Netherlands (2016)

#### **TEACHING COURSES**

**Undergraduate**: Principles of Economics; Statistics for Economics and Business; Development Economics, Econometrics, Mathematical Economics

# ARTICLES PUBLISHED IN CITATION JOURNAL

- Muhammad Daaniyall Abd Rahman, Zaleha Mohd Noor and Law Siong Hook (2013). Short Run and Long Run Ricardian Equivalence? An Evidence from Malaysia. *Journal of Social Sciences and Humanities*. 21(S). (Scopus)
- 2. Mohd Yusof Saari, Azman Hassan, **Muhammad Daaniyall Abd Rahman** and Azali Mohamed. (2014). Evaluation of the relative performance of RAS and cross-entropy techniques for updating input-output tables of Malaysian, *Malaysian Journal of Economic Studies*, 51(2), 77-89. (Scopus)
- 3. Mohd Yusof Saari, Azman Hassan, Muhammad Daaniyall Abd Rahman and Azali Mohamed. (2014). Evaluation of the relative performance of RAS and cross-entropy techniques for updating input-output tables of Malaysian, *Malaysian Journal of Economic Studies*, 51(2), 77-89. (Scopus)
- Lenzen M., A. Geschke, M.D. Abd Rahman, Y. Xiao, E. Dietzenbacher, S. Inomata, K. Kanemoto, B. Los, D. Moran, R. Reyes, H. Schulte in den Bäumen, A. Tukker, T. Walmsley, T. Wiedmann, R. Wood and N. Yamano (2017) The Global MRIO Lab Charting the World Economy. Economic Systems Research. 29(2): 158-156 (Q1)
- M.D. Abd Rahman, B. Los, A. Geschke, Y. Xiao, K. Kanemoto, and Lenzen M. (2017) A
  Flexible Adaptation of the WIOD Database in a Virtual Laboratory. Economic Systems Research. 29(2): 187-208 (Q1)

# MUHAMMAD DAANIYALL ABD RAHMAN

Department of Economics, Faculty of Economics and Management, Universiti Putra Malaysia, 43400 Serdang, Selangor Tel: +603-8946 7019 | Fax: +603-8948 6188 | Email: daaniyall@upm.edu.my | Email: daaniyall@gmail.com

Institute of Agriculture and Food Policy Studies, Universiti Putra Malaysia, Putra-Infoport, Jalan Kajang-Puchong, 43400 Serdang, Selangor Tel: +603-8947 1097 | Fax: +603-8943 2611 | Email: daaniyall@upm.edu.my | Email: daaniyall@gmail.com

### TRAINING MODULES

(Author, Year, Module title, Organization)

- 1. Mohd Yusof Saari. Muhammad Daaniyall Abd Rahman, Chakrin Utit, Umi Zakiah Norazman and Lee Zen Yi, 2018, "Kursus Kajian Impak Teknologi Nuklear Kepada Sosio-Ekonomi Negara: Modul 1". Malaysian Nuclear Agency
- 2. Mohd Yusof Saari. Muhammad Daaniyall Abd Rahman, Chakrin Utit, Umi Zakiah Norazman and Lee Zen Yi, 2017, "Input-Output Approach for Global Value Chain Analysis". Ministry of International Trade and Industry

## RESEARCH PROJECTS

(Title, Year, Funds, Status—Position)

- 1. Distributional Effects of GST to Malaysian Living Cost: A Top-Down Approach using Input-Output Analysis, 2018, PNB Research Institute (Private Grant)—Co-researcher
- 2. Input-output Modelling to Predict Sectoral Multiplier Effect, 2018, SME Corporation—Co-researcher

## **CONSULTANCY**

(Title, Year, Project—Position)

- 1. Study on "Environmental Scan: Food and Beverages Sector: Expansion on the Halal Industry", 2018, Institute of Labour Market Information and Analysis (ILMIA)—Consultant
- 2. Study on "Agricultural Transformation and Inclusive Growth: The Malaysian Experience", 2018, World Bank—Consultant
- 3. Study on "Impact of Exports to the Malaysian Economic", 2013, Malaysia External Trade Development Corporation (MATRADE)—Consultant
- 4. Baseline Study on Awareness of Competition Act 2010 in Malaysia, 2013, Malaysia Competition Commission (MYCC)—Consultant
- Forecasting Malaysia Trade Ranking in 2020, 2012, Malaysia External Trade Development Corporation (MATRADE)— Consultant

## **JOURNAL REVIEWER**

(Paper title, Name of Journal, Year)

1. Pursuing More Sustainable Energy Consumption by Analyzing Sectoral Direct and Indirect Energy Use in Malaysia, *International Journal of Economics and Management*, 2018.

# MUHAMMAD DAANIYALL ABD RAHMAN

Department of Economics, Faculty of Economics and Management, Universiti Putra Malaysia, 43400 Serdang, Selangor Tel: +603-8946 7019 | Fax: +603-8948 6188 | Email: daaniyall@upm.edu.my | Email: daaniyall@gmail.com

Institute of Agriculture and Food Policy Studies, Universiti Putra Malaysia, Putra-Infoport, Jalan Kajang-Puchong, 43400 Serdang, Selangor Tel: +603-8947 1097 | Fax: +603-8943 2611 | Email: daaniyall@upm.edu.my | Email: daaniyall@gmail.com

## TRAINING/SEMINAR/CONFERENCE ATTENDED

(Name of Training Attended, Location, Year, Role)

- 1. Blended Learning with PutraBLAST, Universiti Putra Malaysia, 2018—Participant
- 2. Research Proposal Coaching Workshop, Universiti Putra Malaysia, 2018—Participant
- 3. Kursus Kajian Impak Teknologi Nuklear Kepada Sosio-Ekonomi Negara: Modul I, Malaysian Nuclear Agency, 2018—Trainer
- 4. 3rd Capacity Building Workshop on Strategic Framework on Measurement of APEC TiVA under GVCs & its Action Plan, Nanning, China, 2017—Participant
- 5. Closing Regional Workshop for the United Nations Development Account Project "Supporting Member States in Developing and Strengthening Environment Statistics and Integrated Environmental-Economic Accounting for Improved Monitoring of Sustainable Development", Jakarta, Indonesia, 2017 Participant
- 6. Input-Output Approach for Global Value Chain Analysis Workshop at the Ministry of International Trade and Industry Malaysia, 2017—Trainer
- 7. 24<sup>th</sup> International Input-Output Conference & 6<sup>th</sup> Edition of the International School of I-O Analysis, Seoul, South Korea, 2016—Presenter
- 8. 23<sup>rd</sup> International Input-Output Conference & 5<sup>th</sup> Edition of the International School of I-O Analysis, Mexico City, 2015—Presenter
- 9. IELab Conference, Sydney, Australia, 2015—Presenter
- 10. Kursus Kenegaraan Pelajar Melanjutkan Pelajaran ke Luar Negara, Kuala Lumpur, 2012—Participant
- 11. Malaysian Ministry of Higher Education Research Outcome Seminar, Negeri Sembilan, 2012—Presenter
- 12. National Research and Innovation Conference for Graduate Students in Social Sciences, 2012—Presenter

#### RECOGNITION

(Role, Type of Service, Year)

#### **National**

1. Expert Reference, Malaysia Technical Working Group (MTWG) for APEC Trade in Value-Added (TiVA) Database, 2017

#### PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

(Task, Year)

#### University

Committee member of COPPA Accreditation for Bachelor of Economics, Faculty of Economics and Management, 2012

## REFERENCES

#### 1. Professor Manfred Lenzen

Professor of Sustainability Research at the University of Sydney, Australia

Editor, Economic System Research (ESR) Journal

Tel: +61 2 9351 5985

Email: manfred.lenzen@sydney.edu.au

Web: http://sydney.edu.au/science/people/manfred.lenzen.php

#### 2. Dr Mohd Yusof Saari

Senior Lecturer at Universiti Putra Malaysia

Tel: +603 8946 7019

Email: mysaari@gmail.com / yusofsaari upm@upm.edu.my

Web: http://www.econ.upm.edu.my/jabatan/ekonomi/staf\_akademik-32888